IFEOLUWA F. OYELADE

hefeeoye@gmail.com • 07068289765

12, Godwin Omonua Street, Isolo, Lagos.

SUMMARY

An inquisitive, enthusiastic and hardworking researcher trained in molecular biology and biochemistry, with strong communication skills developed from extensive teaching experience and ability to work independently or as part of a team. Special expertise in the following areas:

• Experimental Design

• Food Biochemistry

Toxicology

Data Analysis

• Critical Literature Review

Analytical Writing

EDUCATION

University of Sheffield Sheffield Sheffield, United Kingdom.

Masters of Biomedical Sciences November, 2018

Grade - Merit

Covenant University Ota, Nigeria.

Postgraduate Diploma in Biochemistry and Molecular Biology June, 2016

Grade - Distinction (GPA: 4.71/5.00)

Obafemi Awolowo University Ile-Ife, Nigeria.

B.Sc in Biochemistry March, 2014.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Sheffield, UK

2017 - 2018

Masters Researcher

- Generated an expression plasmid by Molecular Biology techniques such as PCR, Restriction digest and ligation.
- Performed mammalian cell culture.
- Performed assays such as DNA damage analysis and cell fractionation on HeLa cells.
- Performed quantitative Western blot analysis of different proteins.

Covenant University, Nigeria

2015 - 2016

Postgraduate Diploma Researcher

- Developed an experimental procedure to determine the hepatotoxic effects of acetaminophen overdose on rats
- Identified the hepatoprotective properties of Celocia argentea on acetaminophen induced liver damage in rats.
- Performed data analysis by SPSS and graph pad prism.

Obafemi Awolowo University, Nigeria

2008 - 2013

Undergraduate Researcher

- Performed antioxidant assays on turmeric powder.
- Performed data analysis using graph pad prism.

IFEOLUWA F. OYELADE

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Medilag Consult Prenatal Diagnosis & Therapy Centre, Nigeria.

2016

Laboratory Scientist

- Obtained blood samples from patients by venepuncture.
- Worked in Biochemistry unit to run a series of hormonal tests on pregnant women and couples with fertility problems.
- Maintained a detailed record of all tests performed for research purposes.

Abiodun Atiba Memorial Institute, Nigeria.

2014-2015

Biology Instructor

- Designed teaching plan to ensure that the curriculum is covered within the allocated time.
- Taught and accessed about 100 senior secondary students.
- Assisted in giving presentations to students about health and wellness during extracurricular activities.

Crown Flour Mills, Nigeria.

2012

Quality Control Officer

- Performed assays to ensure the nutritional value of noodles produced in the company.
- Ensured the products are well sealed, packaged and labelled.
- Responsible for taking note of the daily downtime to give room for improvement.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Sheffield Nigerian Students, University of Sheffield, UK

2017 - 2018

Treasurer

- Ensured the Union gets access to all grants and scholarship from the university.
- Assisted to organise social and Educational events.
- Ensured the finances of the union is well managed and accounted for.

Toxicology Laboratory Group, Obafemi Awolowo University, Nigeria

2012 - 2013

Head

- Ensured all group members have access to information to assist with the research.
- Served as the treasurer and made sure the finances of the group are spent only towards the research goal.
- Worked closely with all group members to ensure that the laboratory is kept in good conditions.

SKILLS

Computer: Proficient in Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, Graph-pad Prism and SPSS.

Laboratory: Tissue culture, Gel electrophoresis, PCR, DNA sequence analysis and Western blot techniques.

IFEOLUWA F. OYELADE

ORAL AND POSTER PRESENTATIONS

- 1. **Oyelade I.F.** Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD); the roles of metabolic syndromes such as obesity and type II diabetes in NAFLD. Poster Presentation at the Department of Biomedical Sciences Postgraduate Seminar, Covenant University. 2016.
- 2. Dokunmu, T.M., **Oyelade, I.F.**, Ogunlana, O.O. and Oladele, F.W. 2016. Hepatoprotective potential *of Celosia argentea* against paracetamol-induced liver damage in wistar albino rats. Oral Presentation at the 6th International Biotechnology Conference, Exhibition and Workshop, June 6 7, 2016. Ota, Nigeria.
- 3. Jones, S., **Oyelade, I.F.** and Pathan, S. Savior Siblings: Savior or Object? Poster Presentation at the Department of Biomedical Science, Ethics, the Law and Public Understanding of Science course, University of Sheffield, UK. 2018
- 4. **Oyelade I.F.,** Maple, L. and Smythe, C.G.W. 2018. First steps in Eliminating Evolution of Drug Resistance in Cancer. Poster Presentation at the Department of Biomedical Science, University of Sheffield, UK. 2018.

PUBLICATIONS

Dokunmu T.M., Oyelade I.F., Ogunlana O.O., Bello, O.A., Ezekiel, O.M. and Oladele, F.W. (2018). Hepatoprotective potential and Histological Studies on Effects of Celosia argentea on Paracetamol-Induced Liver Damage. Covenant Journal of Physical and Life Sciences. 6(1), 8-19.

THESIS/DISSERTATIONS

- Oyelade I.F. First steps in Eliminating Evolution of Drug Resistance in Cancer. 2018
- **Oyelade I.F.** Hepatoprotective Potential of *Celocia argentea* on acetaminophen-induced liver damage in Wister albino rats. 2016.
- Oyelade I.F. The Antioxidant Properties of Essential oil and Methanolic Extracts of Turmeric. 2013.